Guide to the Vassar Student Association Records, 1868-2017
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar Student Association Records
1868-2017
Vassar College. Vassar Student Association
15.5 cubic feet (20 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Records from the Vassar Student Association and its predecessors, including minutes, membership lists, rules and regulations, reports, and other items pertaining to student clubs, self-government activities, dormitory regulations, and other issues and events.
Administrative History
The Student Association began in 1868 through a petition from students. In 1947 the organization was renamed the College Government Association. Sometime in the 1970s it became the Student Government Association then in the 1980s reverted back to the original Vassar Student Association.
Scope and Content Note
Records from the Vassar Student Association and its predecessors, including minutes, membership lists, rules and regulations, reports, and other items pertaining to student clubs, self-government activities, dormitory regulations, and other issues and events.
The material in Box 19 is currently unprocessed.
Access
Other than the restricted material in Box 18, this collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College--Students; Vassar College. Students' Association
Subjects:
Women college students--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Self-government (in higher education)--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--Societies and clubs
Document Types:
Audiocassettes; Financial records; Minutes (administrative records); Reports
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Campus Organizations
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, March 2008. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, August 2023.
Acquisition Information
Original transfer date unknown. Subsequent accruals in 2006, 2008, and 2018.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
The audio tapes in Box 17 will need to be duplicated at the researcher's expense before use.
Series List
- Series I. General Records, 1868-2014
- Series II. Campus Committees, Councils, and Boards, 1893-2012
- Series III. Student Clubs and Organizations, 1892-2006
- Series IV. Miscellaneous Alphabetical Files, 1950-2017
Container List
- SERIES I. General Records, 1868-2014
  - Agreement Between the Faculty and Students of Vassar College, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Annual Reports, 1922-1924 (Box 6)
  - Annual Reports, 1932-1945 (Box 6)
  - Annual Reports, 1945-1956 (Box 7)
  - Budget materials — By-laws, 1988 (Box 9)
  - Budget materials — Financial ledger, 1913-1933; (1 volume) (Box 5)
  - Budget materials — General, 1978-1979, 1983-1985 (Box 9)
  - Budget materials — General, 2001-2002 (Box 9)
  - Budget materials — Requests, 1983-1984, 2004-2005 (Box 9)
  - Committee member lists, 1894-1929; (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Committee member lists, 1915; (1 volume) (Box 4)
  - Committee member lists, 1936-1950; (1 volume) (Box 3)
  - Constitutions and by-laws, 1893, 1901, 1903 (Box 8)
  - Constitutions and by-laws, 1968-1985, 1996, undated (Box 8)
  - Constitutions and by-laws, circa 1996-2006 (Box 16)
  - Elections, circa 1983-1996 (Box 16)
  - Founding documents, 1868 (Box 8)
  - Gavel, undated (Box 4)
  - History, circa 1912 (Box 8)
  - History, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Junior Class record book, 1913-1953; (1 volume) (Box 20)
  - Leadership Conferences, 1997-2005 (Box 16)
  - Lists of VSA officers and organizations, 1981-1988 (Box 8)
  - Lists of VSA officers and organizations, 1999-2000 (Box 16)
  - Minutes, 1868-1890; (1 volume) (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1890-1904; (1 volume) (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1904-1918; (1 volume) (Box 1)
  - Minutes, 1911-1947 (Box 7)
  - Minutes, 1947-1957 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous records (organized alphabetically), circa 1924 (Box 8)
  - Mixed records, including minutes, constitution, and by-laws, 1970-1971 (Box 8)
  - Mixed records, including minutes, correspondence and budget material, 1962-1988 (Box 9)
  - Mixed records, including minutes, correspondence and budget material, 1987-1990 (Box 13)
  - Mixed records, including minutes, correspondence and budget material, 1990-2002 (Box 14)
  - Mixed records, including minutes, correspondence and budget material, 2002-2013 (Box 15)
  - Mixed records, including minutes, correspondence and budget material, 2013-2014 (Box 16)
  - Newsletters, 1988-1993 (Box 16)
  - Notes for officers, 1947-1957; (note cards) (Box 4)
  - Petitions and recommendations, 1916-1917; (1 volume) (Box 4)
  - Register of Student Electors, 1908; (1 volume) (Box 5)
  - Seven Sisters Conferences, 1995, 2000, 2014 (Box 16)
  - Student President - Vassar College Business Administration Manual of Instruction, 1925 (Box 20)
  - Treasurer, 1987-1994 (Box 9)
  - Treasurer and Budget — mixed, circa 2000-2008 (Box 17)
  - VSA Handbook, 1983-1984 (Box 8)
  - VSA Meeting Recordings, 1998-2003; (audio cassettes) (Box 17)
  - [unprocessed material], undated (Box 19)
- SERIES II. Campus Committees, Councils, and Boards, 1893-2012
  - Academic Council, 1994-1995 (Box 11)
  - Black Commencement Committee, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
  - Black Student Services Committee, 1972 (Box 11)
  - Black Studies Committee, 1972-1975 (Box 11)
  - Campus Council, 1968-1970 (Box 11)
  - Campus Dining Review Committee, 2011-2012 (Box 11)
  - Chaplaincy Search and Review Committees, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - College Center Board, 1974-1975 (Box 11)
  - College Planning Council, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Committee on College Regulations, 1990 (Box 11)
  - Committee on College Life, 1994-2000 (Box 11)
  - Computing Committee, 1983 (Box 11)
  - Constitutional Review Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Dean of Studies Review Committee, 1989-1995 (Box 11)
  - Education of Minority Students Committee, 1970 (Box 11)
  - Financial Planning Committee — College Budget Study, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Financial Planning Committee — Minutes, 1973-1975, 1978 (Box 11)
  - Food Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
  - Harassment Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 11)
  - Intercultural Center and Race-Relations Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 11)
  - Overview Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 11)
  - Poughkeepsie Institute, 1997-2000 (Box 11)
  - Race Relations Committee, 1977 (Box 11)
  - Representative Board minutes, 1898-1904 (Box 20)
  - Safety Committee, 1991-1992 (Box 11)
  - Self-Governance Committee documents, 1904-1906 (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1893 Dec - 1984 Jun (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1897 Sep - 1899 Jun (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1899 Sep - 1901 Apr (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1901 Apr - 1903 Apr (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1904 Sep - 1907 Jun (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1906 Sep - 1909 May (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1911 Sep - 1914 May (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1914 May - 1915 May (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1915 Sep - 1916 Sep (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1917 Sep - 1918 May (Box 20)
  - Self-Governance Committee minutes, 1918 May - 1922 May (Box 20)
  - Social Action Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 11)
  - Social Engagement Committee and House Committee reports, 1917-1925 (Box 20)
  - Student-Faculty Committee Minutes, 1924-1927 (Box 20)
  - Student Orientation, 2005 (Box 11)
  - Trustees, 1973-1975 (Box 11)
  - Trustees, 1988-1990, 1992-1995 (Box 11)
  - Vassar Investment Research Committee Report, May 1978 (Box 11)
- SERIES III. Student Clubs and Organizations, 1892-2006
  - General — "Officers and Committees" notebooks, 1892-1911; (21 volumes) (Box 2)
  - General — Miscellaneous alphabetical files, circa 1912-1920 (Box 8)
  - General — "Amalgamation Meetings,", 1922-1923 (Box 8)
  - General — Petitions for VSA Authorization for Student organizations, 1977-1986 (Box 12)
  - General —Rules Governing Campus Clubs and Organizations, 1982-1983 (Box 12)
  - Community Religious Association, 1944-1954 (Box 8)
  - Delegate Assembly, 1979-1989 (Box 8)
  - Delegate Assembly, 1980, 1984-1985 (Box 11)
  - Judicial Board, 1975-1985 (Box 8)
  - Judicial Board [RESTRICTED], circa 1980-2000 (Box 18)
  - Judicial Board/ Court of Appeals—Election Appeals, 1973-1985 (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous Clubs - filed alphabetically, undated (Box 13)
  - Student Activities Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 12)
  - Student Advisory Committee, 1991-1995 (Box 12)
  - Student Conference Committee, 1988-2000 (Box 12)
  - Student Curriculum Committee, 1933-1942 (Box 8)
  - Student Curriculum Committee, 1974-1996 (Box 12)
  - Student Entertainment Committee, 1973-1979 (Box 12)
  - Tempora et Mores Club — Constitution, circa 1907 (Box 8)
  - Vassar Interfaith Council, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Vassar Speakers Bureau, 1970-1995 (Box 11)
  - Vassar Speakers Bureau, 1995-2006 (Box 12)
- SERIES IV. Miscellaneous Alphabetical Files, 1950-2017
  - ACDC, 1994-1999 (Box 10)
  - Administrative structure, 1974-1977, 1994 (Box 10)
  - Admissions, 1969-1981 (Box 10)
  - Africana Studies, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Alcohol, 1974-1993 (Box 10)
  - Attitude of students, 1973-1974 (Box 10)
  - Aula — Café, undated (Box 10)
  - (Jane) Bishop’s Misc Illustrations, undated (Box 17)
  - Bookstore, 2001 (Box 17)
  - Budget crisis opinion forms, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Campus: America’s Student Newspaper, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Campus Dining, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Censorship,free speech, 1975, 1992 (Box 10)
  - Coeducation, 1969-1984 (Box 10)
  - College regulations, 1950-1991 (Box 10)
  - Commencement, 1974, 1991 (Box 10)
  - Communications, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Community Service, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Consumer's Guide to Vassar, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - Convocation, 1974-1981 (Box 10)
  - Corporate responsibility, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Demonstration guidelines, 1969 (Box 10)
  - Diversity - Race, 1997, undated (Box 10)
  - Elections, 1999-2001 (Box 10)
  - Enrollment and class size, 1970-1974 (Box 10)
  - Faculty, circa 1994-2000 (Box 10)
  - Financial Aid, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Firemen and fire regulations, 1974-1977 (Box 10)
  - Governance, 1969, 1975 (Box 10)
  - Governance, 1993, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Howard University - Vassar Symposium, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Library, 1973-1993 (Box 10)
  - Library, 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Life After Vassar Study, 2011-2012 (Box 17)
  - Matthew's Mug, 1975, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Menus, circa 2005-2009 (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous, circa 1999-2004 (Box 10)
  - Multidisciplinary programs, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Nixon impeachment, 1973 (Box 10)
  - Political Activity, 2006, 2009 (Box 17)
  - Politics - Gun Control, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Politics - Immigration, 2006 (Box 17)
  - Poughkeepsie — Urban Renewal, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Poughkeepsie Waterfront, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Public Relations, 1974-1976 (Box 10)
  - Race at Vassar, 1969-1974 (Box 10)
  - Residential life, 1970-1975 (Box 10)
  - Security, 1992 (Box 17)
  - Sexual Assault, 1988 (Box 17)
  - Social Consciousness, 2008 (Box 17)
  - Solomon Amendment, 1983 (Box 10)
  - South Africa, 1978 (Box 10)
  - Space [for use on campus] (Box 17)
  - Strike - Cambodian Invasion, May 1970 (Box 10)
  - Summer Employment, 1977, 1984-1986 (Box 10)
  - Summer Programs, 1978-1980 (Box 10)
  - Sweatshops, 1998 (Box 10)
  - Syllabi, 1983-1988 (Box 10)
  - Syllabi, 1984-1994 (Box 10)
  - Syllabi, 1987-1988 (Box 10)
  - Tea in the Rose Parlor, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - Travel-Student Tours, 1974-1975 (Box 10)
  - Twelve College Exchange, 1987-1988 (Box 17)
  - Vassar College Mission Statement, 2017 (Box 17)
  - Vassar Education — Reports, Goals, 1969-1980 (Box 10)
  - Vassar Institute of Technology (VIT) — IBM, 1970-1971 (Box 10)
  - Volunteerism/Activism — Breast Cancer, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Volunteerism/Activism — Prisoners, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Volunteerism/Activism — Miscellaneous, 1998-2001 (Box 10)
  - Voting in New York, 1999-2000 (Box 10)
  - Women's Center, 1999 (Box 10)
  - Year Round Operation, 1972-1973 (Box 10)